<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on UNCAUGHT EXCEPTION</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on UNCAUGHT EXCEPTION</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 09:06:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Shadowban</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/linkedin-account-shadowban/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 09:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/linkedin-account-shadowban/</guid>
      <description>Hello all.
Six days ago, we published our post about some LinkedIn Lunatics from Portugal. We also made a post on our LinkedIn account where we directly tagged the people we discussed in our post.
A few hours laters, Bloq.it leadership saw our profile, as well as Diogo Mónica from Anchorage Digital. We should note that Bloq.it&amp;rsquo;s Legal Officer was among those from the company who saw our profile, as you can see in this screenshot</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Hello all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six days ago, we published our post about some LinkedIn Lunatics from Portugal. We also made a post on our LinkedIn account where we directly tagged the people we discussed in our post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few hours laters, Bloq.it leadership saw our profile, as well as Diogo Mónica from Anchorage Digital. We should note that Bloq.it&amp;rsquo;s Legal Officer was among those from the company who saw our profile, as you can see in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/YH3S5cm&#34;&gt;screenshot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two days later, our LinkedIn account had been restricted, blocked by an ID request. Since we want to keep anonymity, we did not proceed with said request. We contacted LinkedIn&amp;rsquo;s support team and we&amp;rsquo;re still waiting for feedback. We created a second new account, but we noticed that nobody could find it our even see our content. That&amp;rsquo;s when we realized we had been shadow banned by LinkedIn (we&amp;rsquo;re also waiting for their feedback on this to understand the situation better and how to proceed).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suspected Bloq.it immediately due to what we mentioned above. We do need to emphasize that it is only a SUSPICION. In other words, ALLEGEDLY, we believe that it was Bloq.it who reported us to LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, we decided to change strategies and we published a similar post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/portugal/comments/1fds9co/suspeitamos_que_a_bloqit_bloqueou_o_nosso_blog/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank everyone who commented with constructive feedback (positive and negative). Every criticism, suggestion and support messages we receive give us motivation to keep doing what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d also like to share that we &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/9zYotP9&#34;&gt;contacted Bloq.it&lt;/a&gt; on the same day and that we didn&amp;rsquo;t receive an answer yet. We sent an e-mail through their company&amp;rsquo;s website contact form. If someone knows of a better way to talk to them, please let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until next time,
&lt;em&gt;Uncaught Exception Blog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNCAUGHT_EXCEPTION: &amp;ldquo;DouchebagTechBros&amp;rdquo; tried to stop you from expressing yourself on the internet. Stop web socket connection?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Lunatics</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/linkedin-lunatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 09:06:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/linkedin-lunatics/</guid>
      <description>Dear followers,
This post is about the famous &amp;ldquo;LinkedIn Lunatics&amp;rdquo;. Most of you are probably familiar with the term. For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t, a brief explanation follows.
A LinkedIn lunatic, is typically someone who:
Is a white man Is very wealthy Is completely out of touch with the real world Is a Tech Bro Has perspectives of work that ultimately favour the company and makes everyone poorer except those at the top Thinks everyone can invest in stocks or crypto currencies and get wealthy fast Not all LinkedIn Lunatics check all of the bullet points.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Dear followers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about the famous &amp;ldquo;LinkedIn Lunatics&amp;rdquo;. Most of you are probably familiar with the term. For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t, a brief explanation follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A LinkedIn lunatic, is typically someone who:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is a white man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is very wealthy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is completely out of touch with the real world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is a Tech Bro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Has perspectives of work that ultimately favour the company and makes everyone poorer except those at the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinks everyone can invest in stocks or crypto currencies and get wealthy fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all LinkedIn Lunatics check all of the bullet points. Some do. The most common trait is always an interpretation of the outside world that is completely surreal and out of touch with reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that this post&amp;rsquo;s content is inflammatory (we do it on purpose and we assume it), we&amp;rsquo;ll reject right now any kind of personal attacks to the people who we criticize in this post. Our critics are purely about the ideas that they defend. We don&amp;rsquo;t do personal pesky attacks, because that&amp;rsquo;s worthless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we do have a ranking system in place for our lunatics of the day. Here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S - A lunatic that broke the LinkedIn barrier and jumped off to other social platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A - Totally out of their mind, needs medical assistance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B - One post away from becoming a complete lunatic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C - Raises some interesting points, others are well&amp;hellip; suspicious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D - We can still rescue them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with Mr. Tocha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tocha-startup-spotter--early-stage-investor&#34;&gt;Tocha, &amp;ldquo;Startup Spotter &amp;amp; Early-Stage Investor&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/therealtocha/&#34;&gt;Tocha&lt;/a&gt; describes himself as a &amp;ldquo;Startup Spotter &amp;amp; Early-Stage Investor&amp;rdquo;. His central themes seem to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power of equity as a way to benefit workers more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The power of entrepreneurship as an innovationg engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The worthlessness of accountants in Portugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content creation around building companies and entrepreneurship, where most of the times, suspiciously, the entrepreneur is always the one who risks it all for the measly employees&amp;rsquo; benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jumping on the AI hype train (so much so that every time he needs an image for his post, he generates it, completely disregarding whether or not it was built on top of unlicensed work from artists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want to preface this that some opinions from Mr. Tocha ressonate with us. We applaud his effort of creating educational content, where, for example, he &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_equity-o-segredo-dos-ricos-descobre-activity-7224361755655733248-pdw1&#34;&gt;explains the concept of equity&lt;/a&gt; in a clear and concise manner. We also applaud his opinion that there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_equity-o-segredo-dos-ricos-descobre-activity-7224361755655733248-pdw1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;slave to your salary&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; mentality in Portugal and how we can solve it. We applaud his opinion that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_o-meu-plano-para-solucionar-portugal-activity-7211689382515269632-CjQC&#34;&gt;company-employee incentives should be better aligned&lt;/a&gt; in order to create more benefits for all parties involved. We too applaud his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_portugal-est%C3%A1-velho-n%C3%A3o-porque-temos-muitos-activity-7216335322521976833-oZ-J&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on the lack of innovation in Portugal and how that, combined with other factors such as a government that fails to update itself to the modern era, forces young people to leave their home country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t applaud however, the fact that he thinks that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_os-mais-ricos-em-lisboa-e-a-redistribui%C3%A7%C3%A3o-activity-7206324903065661440-MlWS&#34;&gt;trickle down economics work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t applaud the fact that he looks at accountants as being inferior to him &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_99-dos-contabilistas-n%C3%A3o-trazem-valor-aos-activity-7215965834207252483-Pf79&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_j%C3%A1-te-perguntaste-por-que-pagas-tanto-por-activity-7234855449492127744-LTA7&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t applaud the fact that Mr. Tocha seems to forget that not all jobs offer equity and that because of that, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_riqueza-%C3%A0-portuguesa-est%C3%A1s-cansado-de-ser-activity-7209797282525806592-lw6L&#34;&gt;equity isn&amp;rsquo;t the heavenly solution&lt;/a&gt; to stop being a &amp;ldquo;salary slave&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t applaud the fact that Mr. Tocha seems to consider employees of a company inferior to their entrepreneurs or founders, because they are the ones who always sacrifice everything and more. But sometimes he also defends employees and calls for improvements to their benefits. So which one is it Mr. Tocha? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_j%C3%A1-te-chamaram-patr%C3%A3o-explorador-isto-activity-7218856914091200513-JUHT&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_porco-que-bela-omelete-que-n%C3%B3s-fizemos-activity-7234498060813238272-NXZb&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t applaud the fact that Mr. Tocha seems to think that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/therealtocha_se-n%C3%A3o-leres-isto-os-teus-filhos-v%C3%A3o-acabar-activity-7213421078461726720-5CBP&#34;&gt;certain jobs are inferior to others&lt;/a&gt;. Any profession has its value, and there are people who might be happy just washing dishes! Every one of us should go after what we enjoy the most and what aligns better with our goals in life. Not everything is about creating the maximum amount of wealth Mr. Tocha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Ranking - Class C LinkedIn Lunatic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diogo-mónica-engineer-that-allocates-capital&#34;&gt;Diogo Mónica, &amp;ldquo;Engineer that allocates capital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is Diogo Mónica. We&amp;rsquo;ve referenced him in the past because Diogo has the idea that somehow 10 year old children who don&amp;rsquo;t care about a flute will care about how to do their taxes or how vesting and cliff periods work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who is Diogo Mónica? Co-founder of Anchorage Digital, a company that claims to be the safest crypto platform for any institution. We don&amp;rsquo;t want to go down the defamation route at all, but crypto related companies don&amp;rsquo;t have a very, let&amp;rsquo;s say, polished history. We wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if we saw Diogo in a prison in a few years because it was found that he was a scammer or that he assembled a few Ponzi schemes. We also forgot to mention that Diogo is an investor at a hedge fund. This is starting to get really similar to a story we wrote before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides generic posts that anyone with half a brain and some work experience could write, Mr. Diogo has some strong opinions regarding some topics. Sadly, we don&amp;rsquo;t really agree with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diogo Mónica thinks it&amp;rsquo;s funny to call people &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_people-that-are-skeptical-of-the-waymo-experience-activity-7231360304415145984-JnEx&#34;&gt;dumb&lt;/a&gt; for not wanting to hop in robo taxis that are still at their early stages. It would be far more interesting to explain his defensive stance on Waymo, but it seems like he prefers to be a 10 year old instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diogo Mónica thinks that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_people-think-that-the-most-popular-sport-activity-7214543803649576961-e6UG&#34;&gt;regulations&lt;/a&gt; are for the weak and that everything should be like the grand ol&amp;rsquo; USA where companies can play with people like they&amp;rsquo;re dolls. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_apple-wont-roll-out-ai-tech-in-eu-market-activity-7210221979067441152-XVyT?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;Protecting&lt;/a&gt; citizens? No way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_the-first-5-minutes-of-every-11-should-be-activity-7213165130962903040-eZO-?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;listening to his teammates&lt;/a&gt;, Diogo Mónica preferes to throw them into an AI and ignore the toxic environment or problems that may exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diogo Mónica &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_portugal-is-4th-on-the-list-exciting-oh-activity-7209212430273417217-YdCD?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;doesn&amp;rsquo;t like to pay taxes&lt;/a&gt;! Taxes are bad! Who cares about ensuring a society where there are resources for everyone when I can be extremely wealthy and pay everything for myself from my own wallet? Helping others? What an outrage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like Mr. Tocha, Diogo Mónica thinks that all workers have access to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_trabalhadores-da-sword-health-encaixam-100-activity-7204418221880336384-4Bw1?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;equity&lt;/a&gt; to attain wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diogo Mónica is one of those Tech Bros that would probably &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/en/&#34;&gt;prefer to have all art be completely AI generated&lt;/a&gt; because then we&amp;rsquo;d have cost reductions in producing, creating and publishing art. To the point of thinking that &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:1313/en/&#34;&gt;teenagers would rather know how to invest, fill out their taxes or start companies instead of learning music&lt;/a&gt; (and by the way Diogo, the instrument you had on your post is a transverse flute, not a recorder. You should&amp;rsquo;ve payed more attention in class!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Ranking - Class B LinkedIn Lunatic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;joão-lopes-founder-coo--cro--bloqit&#34;&gt;João Lopes, &amp;ldquo;Founder, COO &amp;amp; CRO @ Bloq.it&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding João Lopes, who we want to give the most sincere congratulations over his success with Bloq.it, we just want to highlight his &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/srlepz_vacations-will-kill-you-elon-musk-activity-7223624298131783680--a0Z?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;inherent workaholism&lt;/a&gt;. A product of his own making, the startup world requires hours and hours of exhaustion and dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we can&amp;rsquo;t applaud the way that this toxic behavior is defended by João Lopes. At this moment he is deluded of something that will later bring him regrets. Not all of us have to work like João. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to. Taking vacation days isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s taking care of ourselves. This workaholism obsession is absurd. You need to wake up at 4 A.M., have a cold shower at 4:01, go to the gym at 4:02, read 10 books at 4:03 and then start work. This isn&amp;rsquo;t healthy for anyone, no matter how much you like your job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Ranking - Class D LinkedIn Lunatic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;miguel-milhão&#34;&gt;Miguel Milhão&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t have to write anything about him. He can go f*ck himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Final Ranking - Class S LinkedIn Lunatic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNCAUGHT_EXCEPTION: &amp;ldquo;LinkedInLunaticsError&amp;rdquo; caught at line 123091 of humanity.js&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The sacrifice and lamenting mentality - perspective from a Portuguese that doesn’t identify as a Portuguese</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/portuguese-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 09:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/portuguese-culture/</guid>
      <description>Dear followers,
This post isn&amp;rsquo;t specifically about the IT world. However, it&amp;rsquo;s something we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to let go of because of how close to the heart this topic is to the person who suggested it.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go.
A lot of young people from the 90s onwards (we&amp;rsquo;re sorry if we&amp;rsquo;re excluding some people from the 80s and 70s who also relate to this), for better or for worse, are a product of a globalized culture.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Dear followers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post isn&amp;rsquo;t specifically about the IT world. However, it&amp;rsquo;s something we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to let go of because of how close to the heart this topic is to the person who suggested it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of young people from the 90s onwards (we&amp;rsquo;re sorry if we&amp;rsquo;re excluding some people from the 80s and 70s who also relate to this), for better or for worse, are a product of a globalized culture. This culture is heavily influence by American culture since Portugal is in the western sphere. But what does this mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means that we grew up with Cartoon Network, Disney, Nickelodeon, FOX, AXN, etc.. A lot of us are probably more knowledgeable about American pop culture when compared to our knowledge of Portuguese culture. This also brought a lot of American ideals to Portugal, like &lt;em&gt;The American Dream&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Pull yourself from your bootstraps&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;If you fail, try again until you succeed&lt;/em&gt;, and more. Modern age Americans are just as ambitious as their ancestors were with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/event/Manifest-Destiny&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Manifest Destiny&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to expand their territories (even though late stage savage and abusive capitalism has sort of been ruining a lot of the world for a few years, but&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s not go there). This philosophies of an extreme ambition, to follow your own goals and trying until you get it right, aren&amp;rsquo;t completely positive nor completely negative. We won&amp;rsquo;t go there either. The important thing to extract here is that a lot of young people in Portugal had these ideals injected into their minds since childhood, and that ended up influencing them in their personal and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can testify to what we wrote above about this divine level ambition from Americans by reading articles and studies about who works harder and is more productive when comparing Americans and Europeans. There are numerous references for this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.businessinsider.com/americans-just-work-harder-than-europeans-nicolai-tangen-norges-bank-2024-4&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/4e319ddd-cfbd-447a-b872-3fb66856bb65&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nzz.ch/english/are-lazy-europeans-falling-behind-the-americans-ld.1830156&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://econreview.studentorg.berkeley.edu/live-to-work-or-work-to-live-work-culture-in-the-u-s-versus-europe/&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minneapolisfed.org/article/2003/european-vacation-why-americans-work-more-than-europeans&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;. This ambition got to a lot of young Portuguese folks, but not everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s drill down a bit and jump to Portuguese culture. From the title of this post, you can already assume that our opinion isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be very positive. But before that, we need to go back a bit in history to understand why Portuguese culture is so deeply linked to, in our minds, &amp;ldquo;sacrifice&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;lamenting&amp;rdquo;. Our starting point is one of the 3 Fs (Fado, &lt;em&gt;Fátima&lt;/em&gt; and Futebol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though in recent years it&amp;rsquo;s been diminishing and even people not practicing a lot, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.publico.pt/2023/08/01/sociedade/noticia/portugueses-face-religiao-catolicos-2058660&#34;&gt;Portugal has always been an ally to the Catholic Church&lt;/a&gt;. For every street you go into, there&amp;rsquo;s a Saint of something protecting us. Or even an amazing stage for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://observador.pt/programas/atualidade/veja-as-imagens-do-altar-palco-que-recebera-o-papa-francisco-no-parque-tejo/&#34;&gt;Pope to sit on for a few hours&lt;/a&gt; and then used for &lt;a href=&#34;https://expresso.pt/blitz/2023-10-12-Rock-in-Rio-Lisboa-sai-da-Bela-Vista-e-muda-se-para-o-Parque-Tejo-palco-da-JMJ-c8b1ccda&#34;&gt;music festivals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to imagine how over centuries a religion can influence a country&amp;rsquo;s population and subsequently, its culture. One of the great focuses of Catholicism, as well as almost all religions, is &lt;em&gt;sacrifice&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.catholiceducation.org/en/culture/catholic-contributions/the-need-for-sacrifice.html&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.catholic.com/audio/caf/why-does-god-command-sacrifice&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://wcucatholic.org/the-purpose-of-our-sacrifices/&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;. And in Portugal, we really do believe that this sacrifice perspective spread heavily throughout the population, almost becoming a pestilent disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to go through your life in sacrifice to be considered somebody. We can never have a lot, always very little, otherwise we can&amp;rsquo;t complain that we&amp;rsquo;re living badly anymore. It feels good to us to say that we&amp;rsquo;re in the shit and that our neighbour is better off because they&amp;rsquo;re rich. Wealth and well-being are seen negatively. What you need to do is be poor, and sick, and always be on the down-low and making sacrifices for others. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes someone great in our eyes, because we look and go &amp;ldquo;Wow, that person sacrifices so much and is in such a shitty situation. Congratulations, how did you do it?!&amp;rdquo;. We never think about reaching our own goals, because that&amp;rsquo;s bad. Portuguese people like misery, they like to be living in a crappy situation. They don&amp;rsquo;t want wealth and they don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone else to have it either. If we&amp;rsquo;re doing badly, others should be too. This mindset is very problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We always remember a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dn.pt/opiniao/opiniao-dn/sergio-figueiredo/pobres-que-somos-5166100.html/&#34;&gt;conversation between General Otelo Saraiva de Carvalho and a Swede ex-prime minister Olof Palme&lt;/a&gt;. After the carnation revolution, Olof Palme visited Portugal because he was curious to know how the country would develop itself after tearing down a horrendous dictatorship that severely delayed the country&amp;rsquo;s socioeconomic, technological and scientific development. So Olof asked Otelo, &amp;ldquo;What does Portugal want with this revolution?&amp;rdquo;. Otelo replies &amp;ldquo;We want to end the rich people&amp;rdquo;. Olof answers back, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to end with the poor for over 20 years and weren&amp;rsquo;t able to yet&amp;rdquo;. If this exchange does not paint a caricature of the Portuguese mindset of sacrifice, we don&amp;rsquo;t know what is. We should mention that it&amp;rsquo;s obviously important to regulate extremely wealthy individuals and tax them accordingly. But this doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow anyone to become wealthy. Why do that when you can instead make everyone wealthy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this is lived on a day to day basis. If our neighbour buys a new car, we get upset. If our co-worker grabs a promotion, we get jealous. If a female co-worker tries to ask a male co-worker that their salary is in order to know if she is being discriminated on a gender basis, the reply that one would typically get is &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s none of your business. Desenmerda-te&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Desenmerda-te&amp;rdquo; translates to &amp;ldquo;Unshit yourself&amp;rdquo;. Portuguese use it as a way of saying &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re on your own, figure it out because I ain&amp;rsquo;t helping&amp;rdquo;. This attitude has its pros and cons. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s really bad.). Instead of celebrating others&amp;rsquo; achievements and empowering them to live better lifes, we&amp;rsquo;d rather see them suffer as much or even more than we suffer. It&amp;rsquo;s important to note this doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to every single Portuguese person. It&amp;rsquo;s a generalization. But what Portuguese person hasn&amp;rsquo;t gone through something like this in their lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s change our suffering mentality to a more American perspective. Not one of &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the most important person on Earth, fuck everyone else&amp;rdquo;, but one of &amp;ldquo;if you reached your own goals, I&amp;rsquo;ll celebrate that with you&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll share my salary information with my co-workers to see if anyone is being treated unfairly&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t end with wealthy people. Au contraire, help each other amass wealth, whatever wealth is for you. Let&amp;rsquo;s throw suffering in the garbage and welcome a culture of empowering one another so that we can all live better lifes together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNCAUGHT_EXCEPTION: Class &amp;ldquo;Portugal&amp;rdquo; has suffered a memory leak at feelings.java. Would you like to think positive and empower others?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Ponzi Valley - Tech Bros and bullshitting</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/silicon-ponzi-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/silicon-ponzi-valley/</guid>
      <description>Everyone in the IT world knows about famous Silicon Valley. The heaven of software development, where the best minds join together to create products that change the world. And this isn&amp;rsquo;t too far away from the truth. Many companies, who today have a significant global impact, headquartered in this northern California region. Thanks to unrelentless investments by the American military sector, universities with great scientific research bodies, government regulations that favored companies, and electronic pioneers like William Shockley (don&amp;rsquo;t ignore the fact that he was into eugenics), John Bardeen and Walter Brattain, Silicon Valley is today seen as the place for software developers to be if they want to be someone in life.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Everyone in the IT world knows about famous Silicon Valley. The heaven of software development, where the best minds join together to create products that change the world. And this isn&amp;rsquo;t too far away from the truth. Many companies, who today have a significant global impact, headquartered in this northern California region. Thanks to unrelentless investments by the American military sector, universities with great scientific research bodies, government regulations that favored companies, and electronic pioneers like William Shockley (don&amp;rsquo;t ignore the fact that he was into eugenics), John Bardeen and Walter Brattain, Silicon Valley is today seen as the place for software developers to be &lt;em&gt;if they want to be someone in life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, everything has its cons. The IT sector boom caused rivers of money to be thrown into the region, and in the last few years we&amp;rsquo;ve seen the rise of &lt;em&gt;tech bros&lt;/em&gt;, men, some of them chauvinists and mysoginists (looking at you Elon Musk), every one of them definitely ultra-capitalists, whose motto in life seems to be &amp;ldquo;Work is the only thing that brings me spiritual satisfaction. Money is the only thing that gives me sexual satisfaction. If I see a dollar bill, I have a mini orgasm.&amp;rdquo; We don&amp;rsquo;t want to tell anyone how to live their lives. Our professional career can and should bring you a sense of accomplishment, so that we can feel that we&amp;rsquo;re contributing to society in a meaningful way. The problem is that these tech bros do precisely that. They even say that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/posts/diogomonica_portuguese-teenagers-dont-know-how-to-invest-activity-7198419209054257152-oofh?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop&#34;&gt;music lessons should be banned so that 10 year old children can learn how to do the IRS&lt;/a&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t be too upset Diogo. Or else I&amp;rsquo;ll play the flute!). Because the only thing that matters is money. Always, money. Maximize returns of investment. Maximize the amount of bullshit conversations to keep building pyramid schemes. Pyramid schemes? What?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes readers, Silicon Valley isn&amp;rsquo;t immune from frauds or scams. In case you need some clarification on what a pyramid scheme is, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lC5lsemxaJo&amp;pp=ygUbamltIGV4cGxhaW5zIHB5cmFtaWQgc2NoZW1l&#34;&gt;best explanation possible&lt;/a&gt; here. It might seem unbelievable that such a sophisticated region like Silicon Valley can be subject to such a simple scheme. But it&amp;rsquo;s true. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain it with a short story:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine yourself a software engineer. You have aspirations, like any other engineer, of solving problems. In particular, you want to solve problems that people have. You genuinely want to help people lead a simpler life. To achieve that, you set a goal of creating a robot that is capable of going grocery shopping for you. And so, you take the jump. With the money that you saved over the years, plus a little bit from friends and families (your first investors), you open your company, &lt;em&gt;GroceryRobots&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the company&amp;rsquo;s first year of life, you&amp;rsquo;re doing it all alone. Programming, marketing, management, accounting, etc.. At the end of the year you managed to develop your first prototype, a robot with a GPS system so it knows where to go, some wheels, a screen where you write what you need the robot to bring you back, a small compartment where you can put your credit card so the grocery store clerk can pay what you owe and a basket where the clerk can place the products. You talk with your local grocery store next to your house and you manage to find your first place to test your robot. You know that it isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the first year you notice that you&amp;rsquo;re running out of money. Time to go investor shopping. This is where Venture Capitalists (VCs) come in. VCs are basically companies that have a lot of money that give a lot of money to other companies, so that they can make a lot more money. Fun, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing your adventure, you knock at VCs&amp;rsquo; doors until someone gives you an opportunity to give a &lt;em&gt;pitch&lt;/em&gt;. You show your video of your rudimentary robot going grocery shopping and you talk about how it&amp;rsquo;s going to disrupt the market. Nobody will ever have to go grocery shopping again! But, sadly, this VC doesn&amp;rsquo;t believe in you and sends you away. And so, you repeat this process, until finally, John from the VC &amp;ldquo;Money and Company&amp;rdquo; likes your idea. He accepts to provide you an initial investment so that you can scale your company and keep developing your vision for the future of grocery shopping. You get excited. &amp;ldquo;Finally, someone who understands my vision. Who wants to help others!&amp;rdquo;. This couldn&amp;rsquo;t be farther from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your second year as a company is fantastic. You hire an engineering team, a marketer and an accountant. Your robot goes from a measley prototype, subject to getting robbed in the middle of the street, to something for secure, more effective. But money doesn&amp;rsquo;t last forever. You&amp;rsquo;re reaching the end of the year again and you realize that you need more funding to keep going. And so, you call John from &amp;ldquo;Money and Company&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;John, John, I need more money to ensure that the robot can move away from people when it&amp;rsquo;s inside grocery stores!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look John, things are running a bit tighter here, we can&amp;rsquo;t lend you more money. But look, I know Doug from &amp;ldquo;Company and Money&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll schedule you a meeting with him. Tell him I invested and he&amp;rsquo;ll know what&amp;rsquo;s up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the third year of your company, things aren&amp;rsquo;t going so well anymore. The robot&amp;rsquo;s progress stagnates. The money ends again. John tells you about another VC fim, &amp;ldquo;Money Company&amp;rdquo;, and a friend of his, Tim. Tim is obssessed with AI and cryptocurrencies. In the meeting with Tim, he&amp;rsquo;s not convinced. But you tell him &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re thinking of integrating AI and cryptocurrencies and blockchain in the robot, but without more money it&amp;rsquo;s not possible&amp;rdquo;. Tim suddenly jolts in excitement. &amp;ldquo;Well I&amp;rsquo;ll be damned! Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you say that sooner! I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that blockchain AI with cryptocurrencies is going to be the future. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s talking about it. Look, here&amp;rsquo;s a few extra million dollars. Continue investing on that AI stuff. People are gonna go crazy&amp;rdquo;. And here begins the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the fourth year of your company, the robot goes in the background. What was supposed to be something simple to help ease people&amp;rsquo;s lives is ignored. With a need to have more money, more investments, the focus goes to publicity. Buzzwords. Hype. Creating false expectations. Suddenly, your &lt;em&gt;GroceryRobot&lt;/em&gt; is now able to clean your house, walk your dogs, create paintings, washing dishes, everything thanks to the blockchain AI which will disrupt the market and change the planet. The ecstasy you felt when Tim gave you 5x more than what you needed takes over you, it starts to corrupt you, slowly. The engineers you hired in during your second year quit because they no longer agree with the company&amp;rsquo;s vision. But you don&amp;rsquo;t care. You hire other engineers to replace them. Cheaper ones, so that there&amp;rsquo;s more budget for publicity and marketing. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if the robot&amp;rsquo;s quality gets worse as long as you generate more hype. You start to dream about mansions, yachts, private jets, the luxury life you will soon have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, Tim, John and Doug all have a lot of money in play. They want to get it back at some point. Since they were your first investors, that have a considerable slice of your company. They star to work with you more closely and they always give you references of other investors so that you can keep going with your funding rounds (you&amp;rsquo;ve probably read in the news about Series A, B, C, D and so on). The money keeps coming in, even though the actual value of your company is no longer there, besides speculative publicity and marketing. You start to practice your public image. You begin posting on social media more frequently, with many of your posts being marked as controversial, to generate more attention. More attention means more investment. And that&amp;rsquo;s all that matters now. People who&amp;rsquo;ve bought your product and review it negatively don&amp;rsquo;t matter. &amp;ldquo;The robot can&amp;rsquo;t even get across the street to the store anymore. How can this company say they&amp;rsquo;re disrupting the grocery shopping market?&amp;rdquo;. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, as long as investors keep injecting more money. You&amp;rsquo;re too big to fail. You can&amp;rsquo;t fail. And on the other side, you have your share of supporters. People who&amp;rsquo;ll say &amp;ldquo;Wow, what a revolutionary company!&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;People who talk badly about &lt;em&gt;GroceryRobots&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t understand anything about the industry. Reader is an inspiration to our generation. Ignore the haters!!!&amp;rdquo;. Your ego doesn&amp;rsquo;t get totally bruised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few more years go by, a few more funding rounds go by, and you achieve the dream of any startup. Unicorn status, which means that your company is evaluated at a billion dollars. Your investors tell you &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s time to take your amazing company to the stock market&amp;rdquo;. Even though your company is now a superficial representation of your initial dream, and even though you sometimes still doubt yourself if this is the right path, the money beckons your call. And it silences any conscious thought that what you&amp;rsquo;re doing is imoral, or unethical. And your company, &lt;em&gt;GroceryRobots&lt;/em&gt; is now in the stock market through an IPO (Initial Public Offering). Deep down, you know that the company has nothing, no value. Your stocks will sooner or later be worth 10x less than what they are worth today. So, you start selling all your stocks (or just some of them to not raise suspicions). Your investors do the same. Little by little, you start profiting off the scheme you built with your investors. Your employees, whom you never gave any of your stocks because you need to attract investors, will be out of a job in a few months. The company will crumble, but you still made a few hundred millions along the way so you have live the luxury life you suddenly wanted. What was once a dream to help people shop without concerns will stay in history as a fraud and a failed project. A couple of years late, Doug knocks on your door: &amp;ldquo;I have an interesting startup called &lt;em&gt;CryptoRevolution&lt;/em&gt;, want to invest?&amp;rdquo;. The cycle continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FIN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgive me for the drama of this short story, but this is a good reflection of what has happened a lot in the real world. The most famous example is probably of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/business-58336998&#34;&gt;Theranos and its found, Elizabeth Holmes&lt;/a&gt;. What can we do about this? Well, calling frauds or scams out when they happen is one thing. For the engineers reading this that might be in such a startup company, play the game. Win stock ownership of the company. I know it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to deal with so much bullshit for so long, but think of the end goal. If you can reap what you sowed at the end, use it to better the world at whatever scale that might be. Unfortunately, this is something that is extremely difficult to stop at an individual level. I really do believe that the best move is to participate in this system, and then seed positive change in your community after reaping the benefits. Fight for what&amp;rsquo;s yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more, please watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zU5JsP6pUpc&amp;pp=ygUbc2lsaWNvbiB2YWxsZXkgcG9uemkgc2NoZW1l&#34;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S.: If there&amp;rsquo;s a company called &lt;em&gt;GroceryRobots&lt;/em&gt;, the company that we portray in this post has no connection to the real world company. The short story written in this post is completely fiction. Please don&amp;rsquo;t sue us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNCAUGHT_EXCEPTION: Class &amp;ldquo;Money&amp;rdquo; has corrupted your brain at line 81264781 of brain.go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Software - Intelectual Dishonesty for Workers</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/posts/critical-software-august-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 05:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/posts/critical-software-august-2024/</guid>
      <description>Dear readers, binaries, non-binaries and hexadecimals, engineers, or any other job you may have,
On the day 23/08/2024, there was an information leak from Critical Software - a software house with great reputation in Portugal.
The content of this leak is an e-mail, which tells us the following:
Following the announcement made by our CEO, João Carreira, during Q2&amp;#39;s All Hands meeting last July, we would like to share with you the main changes and updates to our Hybrid Model.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear readers, binaries, non-binaries and hexadecimals, engineers, or any other job you may have,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the day 23/08/2024, there was an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/portugal/comments/1eys8be/critical_software_back_at_it_again/&#34;&gt;information leak from Critical Software&lt;/a&gt; - a &lt;em&gt;software house&lt;/em&gt; with great reputation in Portugal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this leak is an e-mail, which tells us the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Following the announcement made by our CEO, João Carreira, during Q2&amp;#39;s All Hands meeting last July, we would like to share with you the main changes and updates to our Hybrid Model. We understand that change is always difficult, and that moving towards a hybrid model on the last couple of years has been challenging and demanding for everyone. We are conscious that this new change may also be met with some resistance - and that&amp;#39;s ok.

This decision is not a whim: unfortunately, the adherence to the Hybrid Model was not as transversal as we hoped for; also, we do feel that we were lacking collaboration, innovation and even team cohesion in some moments. We truly believe that this was the necessary response to those challenges.

For those of you in Leadership positions and in Support functions, whom will be impacted the most, please do not see this as some kind of punishment, but rather as a natural consequence of your crucial role in the Company. Your presence in the office is essential for setting the tone, promoting collaboration, mentoring, driving key initiatives... we hope that you can see this not as a burden, but as a recognition of your impact and contribution to the success of our company, and for making sure that our community continues to thrive.


Here are the updated outlines of our Hybrid Model:

    1. Compliance to Hybrid
        a. 2x a week at the office minimum applicable to everybody.
        b. 3x a week at the office minimum applicable to:
            Support areas (FM,FIN,INN,MARCOM,PPL,QUA,SUST)
            Seniors C4+
            All Team Leaders (CEO,MB,LB,DD,DOD,CTO,APM,PM,SPM,PGM,PMA,PMSA,PTO,TM,TL)
            All newcomers during the onboarding/ 6 months&amp;#39; probation period
        c. Accountability for team compliance applicable to:
            Senior team leaders: CEO, MB, DOD, PTM, Support Area Directors.
    2. Information
        a. Information on individual compliance provided monthly to each employee
        b. Information on team compliance provided monthly to senior team leaders
        c. All existing dashboards and exception lists adapted and still available
    3. Non-compliance of individuals
        a. Depending on recurrence/severity the implications of non-compliance will be as follows:
        b. During initial onboarding/contract trial period (180 days)
            Any non-compliant, unjustified week will trigger termination of the contract
        c. From then on, within a 6-month moving window
            At 2nd non-compliance week
                1. IPA set to &amp;#34;Partial Contribution&amp;#34; and compensation review frozen
            At 4th non-compliance week
                1. Initiate formal unjustified absence and potential dismissal
    4. Non-compliance of teams
        a. Senior team leaders are fully accountable for the compliance of their team
        b. Within a 6-month moving window
            Minimum 92% of compliance of the team, otherwise IPA is set to &amp;#34;Partial Contribution&amp;#34; and compensation review frozen
    5. Clarifications
        a. Technical Managers (TMs) are defined for every project in Pulsar
        b. Technical Leads (TLs) will be flagged manually by the PtM on Pulsar
        c. For Tomar and Vila Real local hubs, when co-work is available, 2x at the office means 1x office + 1x co-work, and 3x at the office means 2x office + 1x co-work
        d. Tolerating 1 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 25 of 26 weeks = 95%
        e. Tolerating 2 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 24 of 26 weeks = 92%
        f. Tolerating 1 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 35 of 26 weeks = 88%
        g. For team compliance we consider 92% to be a realistic target since there&amp;#39;s factors that prevent compliance to reach 100% related with the timely registration pf absences, exceptions, travel, visit to customers etc. in a group of people. Beyond 2 non-compliant weeks per 6-month period, a discussion over the fir for the role of the team leader should take place.
        h. Non compliances to the policy discredit the policy and discourage those that follow the policy
        i. Team leaders, seniors and support areas have a special responsibility in building solid and vibrant teams, culture, community, create trust, integrate, teach and mentor younger colleagues
        j. On the other hand, the successful integration of newcomers into the company culture and its ways of working requires additional availability to interact, learn and be mentored and coached by team members
        k. Regarding mroe junior leadership roles and responsibilities (such as TL) the additional time required at the office is not only to support, coach and mentor the people they lead but also to lear, be coached and mentored by other leaders in the company, accelerating the development of people leadership skills to build better leaders.

_This Hybrid Model updated policy is effective from September 1st, 2024 (even if systems and/or dashboards may not be fully operational)._


Feel free to reach out with any queries or suggestions.


I wish you all a great holiday season!


#making_the_world_a_better_place
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amongst the several grammatical errors and acronyms, let&amp;rsquo;s try to deconstruct this e-mail. But before that, some context:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the COVID pandemic happened, the remote work model started being adopted en masse due to its inherent advantages for workers in the IT industry. I won&amp;rsquo;t list them here since it&amp;rsquo;s not what we should be concerned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the tides changing, many companies embraced this change (others had already been surfing on the remote work sea) and workers rejoiced everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other companies (looking at you Google, Apple, Tesla, Critical Software and Critical TechWorks) were upset in giving more freedoms to their workers. This is due to several reasons, amongst them, the money that was suddenly lost by renting out office spaces. However, we do recognize that even inside the IT world, there are some jobs which have to be performed in-person. This isn&amp;rsquo;t what we&amp;rsquo;re trying to reject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In onder to avoid exodus of their work force, these companies reached a halfway point. The hybrid model, where the workers work at home and at the company&amp;rsquo;s offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, the success of any work model will depend on each team, each culture, each company. It&amp;rsquo;s not something that we reject either (we aren&amp;rsquo;t in favor of fully remote extremism). Any opinion regarding this subject that is extremist, should be politely ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, these same companies hired people en masse, which would later transform into shooting your own foot because they had to fire them all during the last 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, we arrive at the leaked e-mail, with all the possible acronyms and hashtags of wanting to build a better world. I don&amp;rsquo;t know which world they are making better except the worlds of Critical Software&amp;rsquo;s executives, because the world of its workers has been shut down today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go bit by bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This decision is not a whim: unfortunately, the adherence to the Hybrid Model was not as transversal as we hoped for; also, we do feel that we were lacking collaboration, innovation and even team cohesion in some moments. We truly believe that this was the necessary response to those challenges.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you completely failed in changing your paradigm. And instead of making structural changes to the company (and possible send some dinossaurs away), you decided to make your workers&amp;rsquo; lives worse. Critical, Critical, that&amp;rsquo;s not how you embrace change!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For those of you in Leadership positions and in Support functions, whom will be impacted the most, please do not see this as some kind of punishment, but rather as a natural consequence of your crucial role in the Company. Your presence in the office is essential for setting the tone, promoting collaboration, mentoring, driving key initiatives&amp;hellip; we hope that you can see this not as a burden, but as a recognition of your impact and contribution to the success of our company, and for making sure that our community continues to thrive.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tip for your HR department&amp;hellip; When you write to people that they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t see something as a punishment, generally that&amp;rsquo;s what will happen. What were you expecting from your workers when they read this? For them to say &amp;ldquo;Oh, what wonderful news! We&amp;rsquo;re getting punished! Derek, pass me the whip and the salt would you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now for the juicy part. The specific changes that, as we read before, are, not, a, punishment. Don&amp;rsquo;t tell us we didn&amp;rsquo;t warn you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Compliance to Hybrid
    a. 2x a week at the office minimum applicable to everybody.
    b. 3x a week at the office minimum applicable to:
        Support areas (FM,FIN,INN,MARCOM,PPL,QUA,SUST)
        Seniors C4+
        All Team Leaders (CEO,MB,LB,DD,DOD,CTO,APM,PM,SPM,PGM,PMA,PMSA,PTO,TM,TL)
        All newcomers during the onboarding/ 6 months&#39; probation period
    c. Accountability for team compliance applicable to:
        Senior team leaders: CEO, MB, DOD, PTM, Support Area Directors.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far so good. It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly normal and acceptable that in a hybrid work model there is a minimum number of work days where you have to be in the office. Just a side note: I really doubt that the people at the top are going to be forced to abide by this system. After all, how would &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.campeaoprovincias.pt/noticia/critical-software-oferece-piano-publico-a-estacao-de-entrecampos-em-lisboa&#34;&gt;João Carreira (their CEO) install pianos across Portugal&amp;rsquo;s public transport stations&lt;/a&gt; if he has to go 3x per week to the office?! Unnacceptable. First they take away our remote work, then they take the amazing art of hearing a piano at Trindade or Entrecampos Stations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;3. Non-compliance of individuals
    a. Depending on recurrence/severity the implications of non-compliance will be as follows:
    b. During initial onboarding/contract trial period (180 days)
        Any non-compliant, unjustified week will trigger termination of the contract
    c. From then on, within a 6-month moving window
        At 2nd non-compliance week
            1. IPA set to &amp;quot;Partial Contribution&amp;quot; and compensation review frozen
        At 4th non-compliance week
            1. Initiate formal unjustified absence and potential dismissal
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello, ACT (government entity in Portugal responsible to enforce labour laws)? I&amp;rsquo;d like to report Critical Software for imposing new dismissal conditions without updating my contracts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, whoever doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;clock in&amp;rdquo; to abide by the minimum requirements (which by the way, for an IT company is very modern and progressive!), is fired. People who read this and might be considering joining Critical Software, RUN AWAY. There are better places for you to work. This strategy is perfect for those managers who don&amp;rsquo;t do s*it. &amp;ldquo;Hey boss, I clocked in, I&amp;rsquo;ve done my job for today.&amp;rdquo;. How unaware and ignorant do you have to be to understand that productive people in a team don&amp;rsquo;t need micro management to be successful? João Carreira, careful! If you don&amp;rsquo;t clock in at the office 3 times a week you&amp;rsquo;re out on the streets! It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that you&amp;rsquo;re the CEO, because I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone will be treated equally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;4. Non-compliance of teams
    a. Senior team leaders are fully accountable for the compliance of their team
    b. Within a 6-month moving window
        Minimum 92% of compliance of the team, otherwise IPA is set to &amp;quot;Partial Contribution&amp;quot; and compensation review frozen
5. Clarifications
    a. Technical Managers (TMs) are defined for every project in Pulsar
    b. Technical Leads (TLs) will be flagged manually by the PtM on Pulsar
    c. For Tomar and Vila Real local hubs, when co-work is available, 2x at the office means 1x office + 1x co-work, and 3x at the office means 2x office + 1x co-work
    d. Tolerating 1 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 25 of 26 weeks = 95%
    e. Tolerating 2 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 24 of 26 weeks = 92%
    f. Tolerating 1 non-compliant weeks per 6-month window means 35 of 26 weeks = 88%
    g. For team compliance we consider 92% to be a realistic target since there&#39;s factors that prevent compliance to reach 100% related with the timely registration pf absences, exceptions, travel, visit to customers etc. in a group of people. Beyond 2 non-compliant weeks per 6-month period, a discussion over the fir for the role of the team leader should take place.
    h. Non compliances to the policy discredit the policy and discourage those that follow the policy
    i. Team leaders, seniors and support areas have a special responsibility in building solid and vibrant teams, culture, community, create trust, integrate, teach and mentor younger colleagues
    j. On the other hand, the successful integration of newcomers into the company culture and its ways of working requires additional availability to interact, learn and be mentored and coached by team members
    k. Regarding more junior leadership roles and responsibilities (such as TL) the additional time required at the office is not only to support, coach and mentor the people they lead but also to lear, be coached and mentored by other leaders in the company, accelerating the development of people leadership skills to build better leaders.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaders become bosses. &amp;ldquo;Hey you, don&amp;rsquo;t work remotely all week long otherwise I won&amp;rsquo;t get a career advancements and I might even get fired!&amp;rdquo;. Do these people know anything about leadership? It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it, with these attitudes. A leader is suppose to inspire and colaborate with their team, not be a Grinch and ensure nobody misses work. This just shows a severe trust gap between people. Without trust, a team won&amp;rsquo;t live long. And if anyone&amp;rsquo;s upset at the boss, they just need to organize, work remotely all week so that the team doesn&amp;rsquo;t clock in at the office enough times and bam! Another person fired. Wait a minute, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to notice a pattern&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wish you all a great holiday season!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open the wound a bit more would you? Lack of sensitivity from companies? What else is new&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;#making_the_world_a_better_place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No comments. The joke writes itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you noticed a pattern. Anyone that fails to click in gets fired. Suddenly, the full remote or hybrid model, full of flexibility for workers, becomes rigid and restrict. Why is that? Do you remember when I mentioned above that during the pandemic companies hired a lot of people unnecessarily? That&amp;rsquo;s the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a completely horrendous tactice from Critical Software to fire people without having to pay severance (and we&amp;rsquo;re lucky that Portugal has decent labour laws!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the most disgusting part about it. It is an absolutely intelectually dishonest play. Does Critical Software think people don&amp;rsquo;t realize what&amp;rsquo;s going on? Come on, just be honest for once and tell us the truth! People are used to being run over by companies! Want a hand? Here it goes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear employees,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our flexible remote/hybrid model didn&amp;rsquo;t work because our intermediary managers and our executives are all fossils who still believe micro managing is the most effective way to handle jobs that require a great deal of critical thinking. We also hired way too many people during the pandemic, and now our investors are mad that we&amp;rsquo;re losing money left and right. So we have to fire a bunch of you.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But hey, at least we installed some pianos along the way right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;#making_the_world_a_better_place&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UNCAUGHT_EXCEPTION: Exception &amp;ldquo;CriticalSoftwareIsNoLongerAGoodCompanyToWorkAt&amp;rdquo; thrown at line 345 of intelectual_dishonesty.cpp. Want to play some piano?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
